Guide to the Frederick Fried Coney Island collection
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Architectural and Design Drawings, 1847-1974 undated
  - Subseries II.1 Flat drawings, 1847-1927 undated
    - Pleasure railroads, undated
      - 56, Pleasure railroad, section detail, plan, and elevation of rail, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
        (William F. Mangels. Ink on paper, 20” x 16 1/8” 3 ½” tear at lower left corner½”)
      - 44, Willow Grove coal mine car bodies, plan and section, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
        (William F. Mangels. Ink and graphite on paper, 18 5/8” x 12”, scale 1:12½)
      - 46, Framing plan for car bottoms, plan, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
        (William F. Mangels. Ink and graphite on paper, 14 7/8” x 12 ½”, 1:12½”)
      - 47, Framing plan for car bottoms, [Willow Grove coal mine cars?], plan, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
        (William F. Mangels. Ink and graphite on paper, 15 ½” x 12 1/8”, scale 1:12 Foxing½”)
    - Ornamental details, undated
      - 161, Ornamental detail of cupid figure standing on a twisted column, elevation, undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
        ( [Marcus] C. Illions and Sons. Ink on paper, 19 7/8” x 14 7/8”)
      - 162, Ornamental detail of cupid figure standing on a twisted column, elevation, undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
        ( [Marcus C. Illions and Sons]. Ink on paper, 12 3/8” x 17 5/8” )
      - 140, Sleigh with wolves, elevation, undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
        (M[arcus] C. Illions [and Sons]. Graphite and ink on paper, 20 3/8” x 15 ½” )
      - 141, Decorative panels, elevations of outer, inner, and intermediate panels, undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
        ([William F. Mangels]. Ink on paper, 21 ½” x 15”)
      - 174, Decorative panels, elevations of outer, inner, and intermediate panels, undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
        (William F. Mangels. Graphite and ink on paper, 19 7/8” x 14 7/8”)
  - Subseries II.2 Rolled drawings, 1910-1935 undated
    This subseries consists of architecture and design drawings by William F. Mangels and the W.F. Mangels Company, many for amusement rides at Luna Park and other Coney Island establishments. The subseries is arranged by subject category. Individual items of note include design drawings for the Whip, the Tickler, the Red Devil pleasure railway, and the Switzerland and Sleigh rides—all at Coney Island. Also included are designs for a Columbia carousel, the racing coaster at Point Breeze Amusement Park (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), the Coal Mine pleasure railroad at Willow Grove Park (Willow Grove, Pennsylvania), plans for the swimming pool tank at Palisades Amusement Park (Fort Lee, New Jersey), a full color advertising poster for the Whip, and design drawings for a “kid’s coaster” by the L.A. Thompson Scenic Railway Company.
    - General
      - Pavilion at Coney Island Pier and Boardwalk, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
        (Pavilion at Coney Island Pier and Boardwalk, undated. Graphite and ink on linen, 37 ¼” x 16” Inscribed “Stussmann’s, C.I.” [Minor foxing, 2” tear at bottom left])
      - Unidentified ocean-front building with truss roof, longitudinal section, cross section, and plan; details of trusses and posts, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
        (William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 53” x 25 ¾”, 1:48 [Minor soiling and slight tears at right edge])
      - Tri-partite entrance pavilion for unidentified amusement on rails, plan, front and side elevations, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
        (Ink on linen, 48 ¾” x 19”, scale 1:48)
      - Octagonal carousel building/pavilion, floor plan, elevations, and sections, 1914 January 23 (Box 16, Folder 1)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 49 ¼” + 48” x 35 ½” [Both ends of rolled drawing crushed; three tears along right edge, 2”, 4”, and 6”]
    - Architectural Drawings, 1913 undated
      - Detail of bath house, Palisades Park, elevations, sections, and plan, March26, 1913 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Plan, elevation, and wall section of amusement park showing houses, roller coaster, bath houses, steam room, ocean tank, and beach, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
        William F. Mangels Graphite on paper, 69” x 36” [Minor tears along right edge and slightly ragged top and bottom edges]
      - Plan, elevation, and wall section of amusement park showing houses (sections A to C), roller coaster, bath houses, steam room, pavilion, ocean tank, and beach, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
        Graphite on paper, 55” x 36”
      - Two section details of concrete foundation, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
        (Graphite and ink on paper, 24” x 19 ¾”)
      - Full cross section and side elevation of machine shop at West Fifth Street and Sea Breeze Avenue, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
        William F. Mangels, owner. Ink on linen, 42 ½” x 13 ½” [Minor foxing, roll was crushed]
    - Carousels
      - “Columbia Carousell,” elevation, partial plan, and section details, November 24, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 35 ¼” x 35 ¾”, scale 1:12
      - “Wagon carousell for Columbia,” section, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
        Graphite and ink on linen, 52” x 37 ½” [Foxing along edges and lower right quadrant; folded in quarters and then rolled]
      - Portable carousel, elevation, plan, and section details, June 1, 1912 (Box 17, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 35” x 36”, scale 1:12 [Left edge ragged]
    - The Whip
      - Poster for The Whip, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
        Chromolithograph on paper, mounted to linen, 41” x 28” [Poster has major losses and tears throughout and is detaching from linen backing in some locations; item was rolled and requires steaming and flattening]
      - Overall plan and elevations of entrance designs for The Whip, plan number three, October 1915 (Box 18, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Ink on linen, 44 ½” x 33”, scale 1:24 [Foxing]
      - Plan and longitudinal section of The Whip, October 1918 (Box 18, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Ink on linen, 48 ½” x 27 ¼”, scale 1:24 [Severe foxing]
    - Swimming Pools
      - Plan and side elevation of swimming pool tank, [Palisades Park?,] undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
        Ink on paper, 99 ¼” x 36”, scale 1:48
      - Ground plan of swimming pool for Palisades Park, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 98 ½” x 36”, scale 1:48
    - Double-sided mechanical drawing; plan and section of machinery (obverse) and plan and section of machinery from below (reverse), undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Graphite and ink on graph paper, 32 ½” x 29”, scale 1:6 [Badly damaged, nearly torn in half]
    - Roller Coasters
      - Point Breeze Racing Coaster, elevation of track heights, March1912 (Box 19, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels. Ink on paper, 87 ½” x 31”, scale 1:48 [Ragged at bottom and left edge, minor foxing, major losses at left edge, 9” and 7” tears at left edge]
      - Foundation plan for the Point Breeze roller coaster, February26, 1912 (Box 19, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 80 ½” x 29 ½”
      - Elevation of unidentified roller coaster, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
        Ink on linen, 116 ¾” x 16 ½” [Extremely soiled 12” to right edge and 4” to left edge, and along center crease]
      - Sheet number three, structure and machinery, details of construction, The Kid’s Coaster, April 1925 (Box 19, Folder 2)
        L.A. Thompson Scenic Railway Company Ink on linen, 69” x 19”
      - Sheet number two, elevation, The Kid’s Coaster, April 1925 (Box 19, Folder 2)
        L.A. Thompson Scenic Railway Company Ink on linen, 69” x 19” Incribed “Auer”
    - Flat rides
      - Sleigh Ride, plan of terminal, platforms, and incline, and cross section of track, February1911 (Box 20, Folder 1)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 91” x 36”, 1:24 [Severely damaged, crushed tube, all edged ragged, major losses and tears at right edge]
      - Cross section and plan of The Tickler, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 58 ½” x 26 ½”, scale 1:48. Badly damaged, severe losses and tearing at left edge
      - Longitudinal section of The Tickler, design number fourteen, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 41 ½” x 22 ½”, scale 1:48
      - Floor plan, longitudinal section, and cross section of The Tickler, including detail of elevator and diagram of Luna Park, April 6, 1911 (Box 21, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 71” x 36” Inscribed “Luna Park Checkers” and on reverse [9” tear at left edge; minor foxing]
      - Unidentified flat ride, elevated tracks, longitudinal section and section details, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
        Ink on paper, 51” x 15 ¼”
      - Unidentified flat ride, full size details of track at terminal and on incline, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
        Graphite and ink on paper, 43” x 26” [Upper edge very ragged]
    - Pleasure Railroads
      - Plan and longitudinal section of the Red Devil Road pleasure railway, Twentieth Century Amusement Company, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
        Graphite and ink on linen, 128 ¾” x 18 ¼”, scale 1:48 [Foxing]
      - Elevation of Red Devil Road pleasure railway, Twentieth Century Amusement Company, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
        William F. Mangels Ink on trace, 118 ½” x 23” [Major 26” tear in center of left edge; major loss along right edge; bottom right severely crumpled]
      - Foundation plan for Switzerland Ride, Dreamland, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
        Graphite on paper. 99 ¼” x 30”
      - Foundation plan and cross section of Willow Grove “Coal Mine” railroad, November 25, 1910 (Box 22, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 123” x 31 ½”, scale 1:12 [28” tear and severe losses at left edge]
      - Foundation plan for unidentified roller coaster or pleasure railway, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
        Ink on linen, 108”x 19 ½” [Foxing, badly soiled 12” to right edge and 3” to left edge]
      - Elevation of unidentified pleasure railroad or roller coaster, March1912 (Box 22, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 69” x 27 ¼”, scale 1:48
      - Section details of track (with railcar) for unidentified pleasure railway or roller coaster, March1912 (Box 22, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 35 ¼” x 29 ¾”, 1:12
  - Subseries II.3: Mapcase Drawings, 1911-1974 undated
    This subseries consists of architecture and design drawings by William F. Mangels and the W.F. Mangels Company, many for amusement rides at Luna Park and other Coney Island establishments. The subseries is arranged by subject category. Individual items of note include designs, plans, and sections of several named carousels, including the Columbia, Culver, Feltman Brothers, Wilcox, and Willert carousels. Of special interest are plans and sections that illustrate William F. Mangels’s various design iterations for the Tickler, as well as his designs for a host of other mechanical rides and other amusements, such as the Cake Walk, Human Roulette, the Squeezer, the Tip Top Pleasure Wheel, and many more. This subseries also contains Mangels’s plans for the artificial wave-generating machine that he designed for Palisades Amusement Park (Fort Lee, New Jersey), and pleasure railroads for the Ryan Amusement Company (Brooklyn, New York), Palisades Amusement Park (Fort Lee, New Jersey), Point Breeze Amusement Park (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), and Willow Grove Park (Willow Grove, Pennsylvania). In addition, this subseries also contains design drawings for the “Loop the Loop” rollercoaster by J.R. Worcester for the Loop Roller Coaster Company and for a “kid’s coaster” by the L.A. Thompson Scenic Railway.
    - Architectural drawings, undated
      - Roof construction plan for unidentified building, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 1)
        Graphite and ink on paper, 21 ½” x 21 ¾” [Minor foxing]
      - Plan of unidentified building at Balmers Walk and Surf Avenue (Brooklyn, New York), undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 1)
        Ink on paper, 24 ½” x 11 ¼”
      - Elevation of unidentified building at Balmers Walk and Surf Avenue (Brooklyn, New York), undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 1)
      - Plumbing section of unidentified building at Balmers Walk and Surf Avenue (Brooklyn, New York), undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 1)
        Ink on paper, 24 ¼” x 11 ¼”
      - Plan, front and side elevations, and section of storage building at West Eighth Street and Sheepshead Bay Road (Brooklyn, New York), undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 12)
        Graphite and ink on paper, 36” x 23 ¾”, scale 1:48
      - Plan, front and side elevations of a wagon shed for W.F. Mangels, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 12)
        Ink on paper, 30 ¾” x 18 1/8” [Major soiling along right edge]
    - Carousels, 1911-1974 undated
      - Carousel, cross section and plan for piers and motor pit, October 1911 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 26 7/8” x 18 ½”, scale 1:32
      - Carousel, plan of foundation and motor pit, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 26” x 24”[Tears along bottom edge”]
      - Carousel, plan of foundation and motor pit, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 26 ½” x 22 ¼”
      - Carousel, plan of foundation and motor pit, October 1911 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 23” x 23”, scale 1:32
      - Frank Wilcox carousel, section details and plan of foundation and motor pit, October 20, 1916 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on trace, 21” x 25 ¼”
      - Carousel, plan, section, and elevations, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 3)
        Graphite and ink on paperboard, 228 ½” x 22 ½” [Extremely fragile, two detachments, one corner loss, 3” tear at right edge]
      - Carousel, plan and section of platform, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 3)
        Graphite and ink on paper, 28 ½” x 20 ½”
      - Carousel, plan, March1912 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 3)
        Ink on paper, 30” x 15”, scale 1:48
      - Carousel, elevation, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 3)
        Graphite and ink on paper, 29” x 21 1/8”
      - Carousel, section and elevation, April 23, 1974 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 3)
        J. Worrell Graphite and ink on blueline, 22” x 17”, scale 1:48
      - Carousel, plan, April 29, 1974 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 3)
      - Framing plan for “Galloping Horse Carousel,” December 1925 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 3)
        W. Johnson Graphite on paper, 24” x 20 ½”
      - Columbia Carousel, plan, section, and elevation, August 10, 1913 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 4)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 33 ¾” x 33 ½”, scale 1:12
      - Portable carousel, plan, elevation, and section, June 1, 1912 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 4)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 35 ½” x 35”, scale 1:12
      - “Galloping Horse Portable Carousel (Colored),” undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 5)
        Graphite on paper, 37 ½” x 20 ¼” [Very brittle, torn at left and right edges]
      - Wilcox carousel (Savin Rock, West Haven, Connecticut), section and details, November 16, 1916 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 14)
        William F. Mangels Graphite on paper, 34” x 35 ½”, 1:12 [8” tear along right edge, center]
      - Framing plan for 50-54’, four-horse carousel (“Wilcox carousel”), October 1911 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 14)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 36” x 19 ½”, scale 1:12
      - Millwork and framing details [for carousel], plan, elevation, and section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 14)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 35 ½” x 24”
      - Carousel engine, elevation, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 14)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 24 ½” x 24”
      - Carousel, elevation, August 10, 1913 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 15)
        Willliam F. Mangels Ink on paper, 30 ½” x 27 ½”, scale 1:12
      - “Willert” carousel, elevation, August 10, 1913 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 15)
        William F. Mangels Ink and graphite on paper, 36” x 21 ½”
      - Carousel, plan and section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 15)
        Graphite on paper, 30 ½” x 36 ¼”
      - Carousel, section detail, and elevation of gabled pavilion, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 15)
        Ink and graphite on paper, 33” x 34” Inscribed “Made for Louis Berni”
      - Carousel pavilion at Balmers Walk and Surf Avenue, Coney Island (Brooklyn, New York), side elevation, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 16)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 32 ¼” x 14”, scale 1:48 [Staining and foxing]
      - Boat carousel, foundation plan, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 16)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 35” x 24”, scale 1:24
      - Culver carousel, elevation and plan, December 1913 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 16)
        William F. Mangels Ink in paper, 31” x 36”
      - Feltman Brothers Carousel, foundation plan, December 12, 1922 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 16)
        William F. Mangels Ink and graphite on paper, 36” x 27 ¼”
      - Carousel, plan and section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 17)
        Ink and graphite on paper, 36” x 25 ½”
      - Carousel, plan and section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 17)
        Ink and graphite on paper, 32 ¾” x 22 ¼”
      - Carousel, plan and section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 17)
        William F. Mangels Graphite on paper, 30” x 26 ½” [Very brittle, 3 detachments]
      - Carousel, section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 17)
        Graphite on paper, 38” x 28 ½”
      - Carousel, section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 17)
        Ink on paper, 35 5/8” x 25”
    - Amusement Rides, 1913-1929 undated
      - Hey-Day ride (North Tonawonda, New York), plan and section, August 25, 1925 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 6)
        William F. Mangels Graphite on paper, 23 ¾” x 29 ¾”
      - Aqua Gallery, detail of counter and pool, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 6)
        Graphite and ink on paper, 24” x 19”, scale 1:12
      - Plan of car bodies for Auto-race Course, Willow Grove Park, April 10, 1913 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 6)
        Graphite and ink on paper, 27 ½” x 10 ¼”, scale 1:12
      - Autodrome, June 8, 1929 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 6)
        Graphite on paper, 26” x 14”, scale 2:1
      - Inscribed “Old-style railway car” (Box 15-J-8, Folder 6)
      - [Full-size detail drawing of Sleigh Ride, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 7)
        Ink on paper, 28 ½” x 26 ½”[Edges ragged]
      - Longitudinal section of The Tickler, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 8)
        William F. Mangels Graphite on paper, 36” x 14”, scale 1:48
      - Floor plan of The Tickler, design number four, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 8)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 40 ¾” x 13 ¼”, scale 1:48
      - Floor plan of The Tickler, design number sixteen, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 8)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 41 1/8” x 14”, scale 1:48
      - Ground plan of The Tickler, design number sixteen, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 8)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 41 1/8” x 12”, scale 1:48
      - Automobile Race, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 18)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 34” x 33”, scale 1:48
      - Revolving Barrel, plan, front and side elevations, March1911 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 18)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 23 ½” x 21 ¾”, scale 1:12
      - “Method of Securing Tie-Rails and Bands to Barrel,” undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 18)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 34 ½” x 24”, full-size detail
      - Cake Walk, plan, section, and elevation, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 18)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 40” x 24”, scale 1:12R
      - Funny Stairs, plan, front and side elevation, and section detail, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 18)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 32” x 20”, scale 1:12
      - Motor Chase Kiddie Ride, plan and section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 18)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 32 ¾” x 21 ½”
      - Motor Chase, plan and section, April 1930 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 18)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 34 ½” x 29”
      - Plan of skating floor, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 19)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 36” x 25 ½” [Upper edge ragged; 4” tear along lower edge]
      - The Squeezer, floor plan, sectional plan, and section detail, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 19)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 35 ¾” x 25”, scale 1:12
      - “Teaser Carousell,” floor plans and section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 19)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 36” x 29 ½”, scales 1:12 and 1:48
      - Tip-Top Pleasure Wheel, section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 19)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 40” x 36”, scale 1:12 [Severe foxing, very fragile, 4 ½” tears along center line at both top and bottom; 4” tear at left lower corner; upper left corner detaching; upper middle also at risk of detaching; currently folded in half]
      - Tip-Top Pleasure Wheel, section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 19)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 36 ¾” x 29 ¼” [Minor foxing]
      - Tête-?-Queue, plans and section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 19)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 35 3/8” x 29 7/8” [Abrasions and losses along center fold]
      - Roulette Wheel, plan and section showing machine pit, August 28, 1911 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 20)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 35 ½” x 25”, scale 1:12
      - Human Roulette, plan and horizontal section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 20)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 35” x 21 ½”, scale 1:12
      - Human Roulette, plan, elevation, and section detail, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 20)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 35 ½” x 21 ½”, scale 1:12
      - “Roullitte Wheel,” undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 20)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 36” x 30 5/8”, scale 1:12
      - Roulette Wheel, August 1911 (Box 15-J-8, Folder 20)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 34 ¾” x 24 ½” [Adhesive tape on reverse]
      - Electric Power Swings, front and side elevations, undated (Box 15-J-9, Folder 1)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 39 ½” x 14 ½”
      - Power Swings, front and side elevations, undated (Box 15-J-9, Folder 1)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 32 ¾” x 15 5/8”
      - Foot-operated Swings, front and side elevations, undated (Box 15-J-9, Folder 1)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 33 ¼” x 14” [Minor foxing]
      - Longitudinal section and plan for an unidentified flume ride [Shoot the Chutes?], June 3, 1911 (Box 15-J-9, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 35” x 18 ½”, scale 1:12
      - Wave-Making Machine, plans elevation, and section details, undated (Box 15-J-9, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 35” x 30 ½”, scale 1:12
      - Detail of swimming pool and wave-making machine at Palisades Park, undated (Box 15-J-9, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels Graphite and ink on paper, 29 ½” x 31 1/8” [Extensive soiling at creases and fold lines]
    - Roller Coasters
      - “Coaster,” plan and section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 9)
        Ink on paper, 28 5/8” x 21”; scale 1:4
      - “Cable grip to take care up coaster,” plan and section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 9)
        Ink on paper 29” x 19 ¼”
      - Unidentified ride, mechanical details and stress diagrams (Luna Park), undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 9)
        Graphite on paper, 29” x 19 ¾”
      - Mechanical detail, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 9)
        Graphite and ink on paper, 25” x 22 ½”
      - Power plant for racing coaster, plan and section, undated (Box 15-J-8, Folder 9)
        William F. Mangels Ink on paper, 20 ¾” x 23”, scale 1:12
      - General plan of tracks, circa 1900 (Box 15-J-9, Folder 4)